希斯顿先生  一切都还好吧
Mr. Hixton, is everything all right?
希斯顿先生
Mr. Hixton?
快杀了我吧
Kill me now.
你收到手机话费单了
You got the cell phone bill?
没有
No.
是我的出版商要我写封底评论的书
Uh, books from my publisher for back cover quotes.
等等  手机话费单是怎么回事
Wait. What about the cell phone bill?
没事啊
Nothing.
啊  又来一批要评论的书啊
Ah, more books to endorse.
你怎么可能看得完呢
You couldn't possibly read them all.
没必要看完
Don't have to.
"又一惊悚力作  理查德·卡塞尔"
"A tour de force in terror. Richard Castle."
"此书之于按摩浴池  有如《大白鲨》之于大海"
"Does for hot tubs what 'Jaws' did for the ocean."
奶奶  这有你的信  样式很正式
Gram, there's a letter for you. Looks official.
巴克曼塞巴斯图律师事务所
"Bachman & Sabasto"?
是切特的房产律师
Oh. Chet's estate lawyer.
他们可能走完了遗嘱认证程序
They probably resolved the probate.
你还好吧
You okay?
这封他的遗嘱突然勾起了我的思念
This memory of him caught me by surprise.
你觉得他在遗嘱中有留东西给你吗
Do you think he left you anything in his will?
其实他没必要留什么给我  但如果...
Well, he certainly didn't need to, but if...
天啊
Oh, my.
妈  怎么了
Mother, what's wrong?
我...
I...
一百万
$1 million?
你妈妈肯定很震惊
Your mom must be in shock.
知道她会怎么处理这笔钱吗
Any idea what she's gonna do with it?
如果我够走运  她会为自己置一套房
If I'm lucky, get a place of her own.
要是真能买到就走大运了
Yeah, that would be lucky.
一百万美金在曼哈顿能买到什么房产啊
You can't buy much in Manhattan for 1 million bucks.
哇
Wow.
桌上足球  篮球架  摩托车
Foosball, basketball, a motorcycle--
我敢说这公寓的业主
I'll bet the owner of this place
身家肯定有一千万
clearly had ten times that.
应该是一亿
Try a hundred.
死者名叫杰·希斯顿
Victim's name is Jay Hixton.
他去年在佛罗里达州
He won a cool $117 mil
中了一亿一千七百万彩票
in the Florida lottery last year.
随后他就去了疯狂大购物
And then he went on a serious shopping spree.
绝对是低级错误
Rookie mistake.
听起来是你的经验之谈啊
Sounds like the voice of experience.
嗯  大学期间写出一本畅销书
Mm-hmm. Writing a best seller in college
就跟赢彩票一样
is a lot like winning the lottery.
我六个月就把钱花光了
I spent every penny of it in six months.
还好我不是昙花一现的作家
Good thing I'm not a one-hit wonder.
胸部中了一枪
Single gunshot to the chest.
从火药残余颗粒沉着和瘀伤来看
From the stippling and bruising,
我敢说死者有反抗过
I'd say there was a struggle,
枪支走火了  射中了他的心脏
the gun went off, vaporized his heart,
死亡时间大概是昨晚11点至2点间
somewhere between 11:00 and 2:00 last night.
这把枪口径太大  与射入伤不吻合
That's a big gun. It's too big for that entry wound.
这把枪不是凶器
This isn't the murder weapon.
就说过她会第一时间发现
Told you she'd spot it first off.
射杀死者的凶器是把9毫米自动手枪
Our victim was shot with a 9-millimeter automatic.
子弹直接穿膛而出
The bullet went straight through him.
我们从扑克桌上拔出了子弹
We pulled the slug out of the poker table.
所以凶手可能是逼着希斯顿去打开保险箱
Okay, so maybe our killer forces Hixton to open the safe,
这个宽357毫米的保险箱藏在墙里
The .357 is hidden inside.
希斯顿把它打开  后来他们发生了争执
Hixton pulls it out, they struggle,
-然后他中枪倒地  -这就是中了奖的彩票
- and he gets shot. - That's the winning ticket.
真是难以想象这一小张纸价值竟超过一亿
Hard to believe a little slip of paper is worth over $100 mil.
要是你中了彩票你会怎么花
What would you do if you won that kind of money?
简单  买一辆法拉利
Easy. Buy a Ferrari.
我有一辆  其实没你想得那么好
I have one. Not as great as you would think.
但它们胜在速度够快
Yeah, but they're hella fast.
交通尖峰时段速度跟其他车没差
Fast as every other car in rush-hour traffic.
知道箱里面装了多少钱吗
Any idea how much money was in here?
十万元  保管在银行袋里
$100,000, secured in a bank bag.
这位是雷金纳德·伊斯利
Uh, this is Reginald Easley.
他是希斯顿先生的仆人
He's Mr. Hixton's servant.
仆人  年轻人  我可是传统的英式管家
Servant? Young man, I am a traditional english butler.
我受训于白金汉宫[英国皇宫]
I apprenticed at buckingham palace.
他的保险箱里总是放着那么多现金吗
Did he always keep that much hard cash in the safe?
希斯顿以前家境贫困
Mr. Hixton came from an impoverished background.
他觉得把钱放在身边较有安全感
He found having hard currency around reassuring.
有多少人知道钱放在那里
How many people knew that it was there?
知情者无疑不少
Dozens, no doubt.
他购物习惯看到就买下
He had a habit of buying everything in sight,
从不考虑自己亮出了多少钱
no thought to how much money he was flashing around
也不考虑让他人得知
or how dangerous it was to tell people
家里藏有更多钱会有多危险
that there was plenty more of it at home.
在纽约  那就等同于
In New York, that's like
邀请别人尾随你回家来杀你
inviting someone back to your house to kill you.
那把枪是他收在保险箱里的吗
Did he keep that gun in the safe?
小姐  这点很奇怪
That's the odd thing, miss.
我熟悉这公寓里的每一件物品
I know every item in this apartment.
但却从未在此见过一把枪
I have never seen a gun.
但我知道他在失窃的袋子里
Oh, but I do know he kept a dye pack
放了一叠自爆染色钞票
in the bag that was stolen.
那它会怎么引爆
And how is it triggered?
它连着一个三分钟的定时器
It was on a 3-minute timer
从袋子离开公寓开始计时
that began when the bag left the apartment.
好的  带上一队警员  彻查这片区域
All right, grab some uniforms, canvass the area.
既然钞票还没自爆
The killer couldn't have gotten very far
凶手肯定还没走远
before that pack exploded.
你最后一次看到希斯顿是什么时候
When was the last time you saw Hixton?
昨晚
Yesterday evening.
他5点左右出门了
He left about 5:00.
我相信他当时与他夫人有约
I believe he had made plans with his wife.
他已婚了吗
He was married?
对的  有一个十几岁的女儿
Oh, yes, with a teenage daughter.
他们在我开始当管家前
They'd been separated for some months
就已经分居数月了
before I began to work for him.
显然是金钱导致他们失睦的
Apparently, the money caused some kind of a rift.
我们当时开心极了
We were so happy then.
去了巴黎  罗马旅行
Trips to Paris and trips to Rome and...
买了有加热座椅的车子...
Cars with heated seats and...
然后大家看我们的眼光就变了
Then everyone started looking at us different.
把我们当怪人看
Like we were freaks.
你能看出他们的想法
You could see them thinking,
"为什么是你中奖  而不是我"
why you? Why not me?
无论我们做什么都是错的
And nothing we did was good enough.
所以我们搬来了这里
So we moved here.
理应是个全新的开始
It was supposed to be a fresh start.
那你们为何分居呢
Why were the two of you separated?
那笔钱简直是...就像是毒药
That money, it was... just like poison.
杰不由自主地花钱
Jay couldn't stop spending it,
而尼可...
and--and Nicole...
没关系  妈妈
It's okay, mom.
尼可染上了毒瘾
Nicole got hooked on drugs.
这事对我们犹如当头棒喝
And it was the wake-up call we needed, really.
杰和我从无话可说变成合力帮尼可戒毒
Jay and I went from not talking to getting Nicole clean.
然后他开始把钱用于善事上
And then he started using his money for good.
他在落后贫困的鲍厄里街
He found this soup kitchen on the Bowery
鲍厄里街:美国纽约市一条经济萧条的街
以低级旅馆  廉价酒吧众多著称
找到一家救济处
that was in dire straits.
他说看着那些需要帮助的人
He said that looking at all those people in need
让他想起若不是中了彩票
just reminded him, if--if it wasn't for that lottery,
我们也会是穷人之一
we'd be right there ourselves.
他开始天天往那里跑
He started going there almost every day.
这也让我想起自己是多么...
And it just reminded me of how much...
多么爱他
how much I love him.
你们俩昨晚最后去了哪里
Where was it the two of you ended up going last night?
昨晚
Last night?
他的管家说你俩昨晚有约
His butler said that the two of you had a date.
没有  杰最后一刻打来取消了
No. Jay called to cancel at the last minute.
他说发生了一些事
He told me something had happened,
需要我们俩一起处理的
something that we had to deal with together.
然后我试着问出他到底是什么事
And I tried to get him to tell me what it was,
-但他不愿说  -他是在哪里打给你的
- but he wouldn't. - And where did he call from?
我想是鲍厄里街的救济所吧
The bowery soup kitchen, I-I think.
我们原定就在那里碰面
It's where we were supposed to meet.
他有与哪些你认识的人
And did he have problems with anyone
发生摩擦吗
there that you know of?
没特别想起谁
No one in particular.
他接触的人都很粗俗
It was a pretty rough crowd.
凭我多年来当推理作家的经验
All my years as a mystery writer
我敢说凶手只有一人
point to one unequivocal killer.
-就是那个管家  -是吗
- The butler did it. - Oh.
你想想  咱们处理过那么多案子
Oh, come on. How many cases have we actually had
说真的  有哪桩的疑犯是管家呢
where there's a-a butler as a potential suspect?
如果不是他干的  那真是没天理啊
It would be a crime if he didn't do it.
然后他第二天早晨出现了
And then he shows up the next morning
还报了警
and calls the cops?
挺高明的  不是吗
Pretty clever, right?
说到高明  我注意到在犯罪现场
Speaking of clever, I noticed at the crime scene,
你从没提过要是
you never mentioned what you
你中了彩票你会怎么用
would do if you won the lottery.
我没想过
No, I didn't.
因为是羞于启齿的事吗  难道是艳事
Is that because it's embarrassing? Ooh, scandalous?
其实我真的没想过这问题  卡塞尔
I actually haven't really thought about it, Castle.
所以不是羞事也不是艳事  只是秘事
So not embarrassing or scandalous, just secretive.
真是坏事传千里
Bad news travels fast.
他对待错误态度宽容
The man was generous to a fault.
当他初次来这里的时候
When he first started coming here,
他拿出一张100元钞票  仿佛那只是一张纸
he'd hand out $100 bills like-- like they were nothing.
情况越变越糟  我只得请他收手
Got so bad, I had to ask him to stop.
-为什么  -我们已经吸引了一些坏分子
- Why? - Well, we were attracting a bad element.
但我还是看见希斯顿先生偷偷
Still, I'd see mr. Hixton sneak money
把钱塞给孕妇或流浪儿童
to a pregnant woman or homeless kid.
那是一种强迫行为  好像他必须得施舍
It was a compulsion for him, like he had to give it away
因为自己不配拥有这么多钱
'cause he didn't deserve it somehow.
赢了也受之有愧
Winner's guilt.
这事其实在彩票得主身上很常见
It's actually quite common with lottery recipients.
希斯顿先生昨晚来到这里后
Did anything suspicious happen with Mr. Hixton
有没有发生什么可疑的事
when he was here last night?
你这么一说我就想起来了
Now that you mention it, yeah.
有个男人下午那会一直在附近转悠
A man was hanging around a good part of the afternoon.
-是你不认识的人吗  -从来没见过
- Someone you didn't know? - I'd never seen him before,
当希斯顿先生6点来到时
but he went right up to Mr. Hixton
他便径直走向希斯顿先生
when he arrived at 6:00,
就好像两人认识似的
like he knew him, you know?
过了几分钟  他便一走没回头了
A few minutes later, he left and never came back.
你觉得你能向素描师描述他的样子吗
Do you think you could describe him to a sketch artist?
所以说神秘男子
So our mystery man
去了救济所  等候希斯顿
goes to the soup kitchen, waits for Hixton,
之后把他带去哪了呢
and then takes him where?
他并非死于之后的6小时内
He wasn't killed for another six hours.
为什么要等呢  如果这家伙想抢劫希斯顿
And why wait? I mean, if the guy wanted to rob Hixton,
为何不直接押他回家  抢空他的保险箱呢
why not just take him home and empty his safe?
还有希斯顿的枪有怎么说呢
And then there's Hixton's gun.
为什么他需要枪  他又是从哪弄来的呢
Why did he need it and where did he get it?
根据鉴证人员反馈  枪是从非法途径得来的
Well, according to C.S.U., nowhere legal.
序列号与枪支对不上号
The serial numbers were filed off the gun,
而且希斯顿胸部的子弹上有他自己的指纹
and Hixton's prints were on the bullets in the chamber,
也就是说枪是他亲自上膛的
which means he loaded it himself.
找到彩票得主的钱袋了
Found our lottery winner's money bag.
-你在哪里找到的  -希斯顿那栋楼的后巷
- Where'd you find it? - Alley behind Hixton's building.
袋是空的  但如你所见
It was empty, but as you can see,
袋里的自爆染色钞票爆破了
the dye pack in the bag went off.
凶手的手一定染上了染料
And it must have gotten on our killer's hands,
因为我们找到了指纹
because we got prints
一个叫托德·希普利的人留下的
belonging to one Todd Shipley,
他是希斯顿那栋楼的维修工
a maintenance worker in Hixton's building.
他下班那会  希斯顿刚好就遇害了
He got off right around the time that Hixton was killed.
但是如果他是维修工的话
Yeah, but if he's a maintenance worker,
他完全可以等染色钞票
he could've picked up the bag
-爆破后再拿钱走人啊  -我想他没那么聪明
- after the dye pack went off. - I don't think so.
那家伙要么是《阿凡达》的粉丝
Either that guy really likes "Avatar"...
要么就是本案的凶手
Or he's our killer.
我发誓  我是在地上发现那个袋子的
I swear. I found the bag on the ground,
我一打开  袋子便冲着我脸爆炸了
and when I opened it, it went off in my face.
那个袋子装了个3分钟定时器
That bag was on a 3-minute timer.
你是想告诉我们
Are you telling us that you
你刚巧在不恰当的时机无意间捡到了袋子吗
accidentally picked it up at exactly the wrong time?
老兄  我说的都是实话
Man, I'm telling the truth.
我那时刚下班  想停下买罐汽水
I-I had just gotten off work, stopped to get a soda,
就看见有一个人从小巷跑了出来
when I saw someone running out of the alley.
你说看到有个人跑出来  那人是什么样子的
This, uh, someone that ran away, what did they look like?
我不知道  周围很暗
I-I don't know. It--it was dark.
托德  如果你再不说实话
So's your future, Todd,
那你的未来就危险了
if you don't start telling us the truth.
老兄  我句句属实  你去问韩货店的李先生
Man, I am. Yo, ask Mr. Lee at the korean grocery.
他就是卖我汽水的人
He--he--he's the one that sold me the soda.
定时器设定了3分钟自爆
Timer was set for three minutes.
他不可能在
There's no way he could've
染色钞票自爆前
gotten downstairs from the 20th floor
从20楼下来  还买了罐饮料
and bought a drink before the dye pack exploded.
好吧  告诉我  你上班期间有在大楼里
All right, tell me this--did you see Hixton in the building
-见过希斯顿吗  -有
- at all during your shift? - Yeah.
他11点左右回到家时我刚好在大堂
I was in the lobby when he came home, around 11:00.
他满身大汗  好像走路回来似的
Uh, he was sweating like he had been walking.
看他提前下了凯迪拉克  我便问他
And since he left earlier in his Escalade, I asked him
他的车在哪里
where his car was.
他说某人从他那开走了
He said someone had taken it from him.
李先生证实了希普利不在场证言
So Mr. Lee confirmed Shipley's alibi.
希斯顿的车确实不见了
And Hixton's car is definitely missing.
希斯顿遇害当天
Well, it can't be a coincidence
车子也不见了  这绝不可能是巧合
that on the same day Hixton's car was taken, he was killed.
凶手可以在抢车那时顺便抢了
The killer could've gotten Hixton's home key
希斯顿家的钥匙
when he took his ride.
驾照上有家庭地址
Address was on the registration.
凶手那么爱这辆车
He liked the car so much,
他会开车去抢劫公寓
he drove over to rob the apartment,
结果当场被抓包
got caught in the act.
那为何希斯顿要回家呢
Yeah, but why would Hixton go home?
-他为什么不报警说车子失窃了  -好的
- Why wouldn't he call the police, report the theft? - Okay.
追踪公司锁定了希斯顿那辆凯迪拉克的位置
Tracking company's got a lock on Hixton's Escalade.
看来车子正在运河街往西开
Looks like it's heading west on Canal Street.
那是荷兰隧道
That's the Holland Tunnel.
凶手正在潜逃
Our killer's making a run for it.
翻译：大卫熊  咖啡十三  千花  Cam小池
时间轴：Jimmy贝壳  千花   后期：瓜瓜   校对&总监：安小七
这人叫肖恩·约克
Name's Shawn York.
泽西市警方在收费高速路上
Jersey police caught him
抓到他正开着希斯顿的车
driving Hixton's car down the turnpike.
但是没发现失窃的钱
No sign of the stolen money, though.
无意冒犯泽西市的同僚
No disrespect to our Jersey brethren,
但我们再检查车子一遍吧
but let's check that car again,
查清楚钱
make sure that that money's
有没有藏在车门或轮舱里
not hidden behind a door panel or inside the wheel well.
收到
You got it.
莱恩  要是你中了彩票你会怎么花
Hey, Ryan. What would you do if you won the lottery?
开酿酒厂
Winery.
听见没  谁都想过这问题
See? Everyone thinks about it.
大家都想过什么
Everybody thinks about what?
要是他们中了彩票会怎么花
What they would do if they won the lottery.
买一艘60英尺长的大游艇
A big-ass boat--60-footer--
船首挂幅硕大的大三角帆
monster spinnaker hanging off the bow,
船尾再挂两根深海鱼竿
two deep-sea rods hanging off the stern.
-不错  -好了  你们就继续幻想
- Sweet. - Okay, while you guys are fantasizing
鱼竿的尺寸吧
about the size of your rods,
我要去审问本案的疑犯了
I'm gonna go and interrogate our suspect.
我可以要一罐
Can I get a...
汽水吗
soda?
我不是空姐
I'm not your flight attendant.
我是凶杀案探长
I'm a homicide detective.
凶杀案
Homicide?
你脚步遍布各地啊  肖恩
You're a bit of a rambler, Shawn.
在厄尔巴索伤人
Assault in El Paso,
在孟菲斯非法侵入
criminal trespass in Memphis,
现在又在纽约市犯下一级谋杀
and now first-degree murder in New York City.
等等  暂停
Wait. Time-out.
我杀谁了
Who did I kill?
杰·希斯顿
Jay Hixton.
不  我见到他的时候他还活着
No. He was alive when I saw him.
那是在救济所  你偷他车的时候
That was at the soup kitchen where you jacked his car,
但后来你贪念又起
but then you got greedy and
跟踪他到了他的公寓
you followed him to his apartment.
他死了  你拿到了10万美金
He ends up dead, you end up 100 grand richer.
我没杀他
I didn't kill the guy.
我也肯定没偷他的车
And I sure as hell didn't steal his car.
那你怎么会开他的车呢
Well, then how did you end up driving his car?
他送给我的
He gave it to me.
他给你一辆7万美金的车  他为什么要那么做
He gave you a $70,000 car? Why would he do that?
我听说
Look, I heard on the street,
希斯顿相信时来运转一说
Hixton believed in second chances,
所以我找到他  告诉他我不走运
so I tracked him down, told him I was down on my luck.
希斯顿说他没带他的支票簿
And Hixton said that he didn't have his checkbook,
问我想不想要他的车
but did I want his car?
我以为他在整蛊我
I thought he was yanking my chain.
谁会给别人车啊
Who does that?
但是他签了产权转让
But, you know, he signed over the title
给了我车钥匙
and handed me the keys.
他就是签了产权转让  没别的了
He just signed over the title, just like that?
是的  女士
Yes, ma'am.
他说他不再需要那辆车了
Said he wasn't gonna need it anymore.
昨晚午夜的时候你在哪
Where were you last night at midnight?
我去我公寓附近看午夜场电影了
I went to the late movie near my apartment.
他们在播放托尼·贾专场
They're having a Tony Jaa marathon.
我现在能喝汽水了吗
Can I have that soda now?
电影院的员工确认卖给过约克电影票
Theater clerk confirms selling York the ticket,
汽车产权是上希斯顿的签名是真的
And Hixton's signature on the car title is authentic.
谁会送别人自己的车啊
Who gives away their car?
能买得起一千辆新车的那种人
Someone who can afford to buy a thousand new ones.
六点  希斯顿把车送给了约克
So at 6:00, Hixton gives York his car,
然后到了八点
and then at 8:00,
他给妻子打电话取消了晚餐
he calls his wife and cancels dinner.
告诉她他们需要谈一些事情
Told her that there's something they need to talk about,
这事情需要他们两个一起去面对
something that they both need to deal with together.
他在十一点到家  而一个小时后
Then he gets home at 11:00, and about an hour later,
他被杀了  那么这段时间他在干什么
he's killed. So what was he doing in the meantime
跟谁在一起呢
and with whom?
你知道那个人喜欢花钱吧
You know the guy did like to spend money?
如果昨晚他用信用卡消费了
If he made any charges on his credit card last night,
消费单可能帮助我们知道他去哪了
it might give us a clue as to where he was.
就算被杀当晚他花过钱  那也是用的现金
If he spent any money the night he was killed, it was cash.
他的32张信用卡均没有消费记录
There were no charges on any of his 32 credit cards.
-32张信用卡  -冰球联盟套卡  一个队一张
- 32 credit cards? - Yeah. One for every NFL team.
这还只是冰山一角
And that's just the tip of the iceberg.
他还买了一匹赛马
He also bought a racehorse,
内衣橄榄球队的小股东
minority stake in a lingerie football team,
还有一辆宾利  现在待在
and a bentley, which is currently
哈德逊河的河底
at the bottom of the Hudson River
因为车子在他租的船上被他开下了河
because he drove it off of a boat he was renting.
天啊  看来那笔钱在一段时间内
Wow. Sounds like that money really turned Hixton
真的是把希斯顿变成了一个不一样的人
into a different person for a little while.
钱不会改变人的本性
Yeah, money doesn't change who you are.
它会放大你的个性
It just magnifies your personality.
也不是都挥霍了
Well, it wasn't all bad.
他还给卖给他
He also bought a house
那张彩票的员工买了一栋房子
for the clerk that sold him the winning ticket,
为死去的邻居买了陵墓
a mausoleum for his dead neighbor,
-还在月球上买了3英亩地  -不是吧
- and 3 acres on the moon. - Get outta town.
他这个刚好在我那个坑的下面
He's right down the crater from me.
你在月球上有财产
Why doesn't it surprise me
我怎么一点都不惊讶呢
that you have property on the moon?
随你怎么挤兑我
You know what? Laugh it up.
等地球变成干涸的空壳时
When the earth is a desiccated husk,
你会求我
you will be begging to
让你住在我的酒海盆地的
come live with me in the nectaris basin.
车我查过了
So I searched the car.
抱歉  约克不是凶手
Oh. Yeah, sorry. York is not our guy.
没事  泽西收押所每年这个时候都很"不错"
That's okay. Jersey impound lot's nice this time of year.
没找到钱  但是我找到了这个
So no money, as expected, but I did find this.
照相机吗
A camera?
卡在前座的下面  肯定是希斯顿的
Lodged under the front seat. Clearly it belongs to Hixton.
这是监视照片
These are surveillance photos.
是啊  不少呢  日期显示是上周
Yeah, a dozen of 'em, date stamped last week.
希斯顿在跟踪这个家伙
Hixton was following this guy.
好的  联系他家人和管家
All right, contact the family and butler,
看他们认不认识他
see if anyone recognizes him.
同时  我们的
Meanwhile, we've got a hole
时间线还有空缺需要补上
in our timeline that needs to be plugged.
我们知道希斯顿八点钟打电话给老婆
So we know that Hixton called his wife at 8:00 p.m.
我们知道他不在救济所
And we know he wasn't at the soup kitchen.
查查手机定位  看看有没有人知道他在哪
Let's ping the carrier, see if they know where he was.
好的
All right.
怎么
What?
你会辞掉工作吗
Would you quit your job?
如果你中了彩票  你会不当警察吗
If you won the lottery, would you quit being a cop?
那我干什么
Well, what else would I do?
超模  脑外科医生
Super model, brain surgeon,
-美国角斗士  -被你说中了  卡塞尔
- American gladiator. - Oh, you got me there, Castle.
我一直想退出警局
I've always wanted to leave the force
成为美国角斗士
and become an American gladiator.
你为什么不想告诉我
Why don't you want to tell me?
因为没什么可说的
Because there's nothing really to tell.
-得了  你肯定有梦想  -当然
- Come on. You must have a dream. - Sure I do.
解决这个案子  回家  泡个爽爽的澡
Solve this case, go home, take a nice long bath.
但是看起来今晚是没戏了
But it doesn't look like that's going to happen tonight.
希斯顿的电话运营商
Hixton's phone carrier.
埃斯波西托
Hey, Esposito.
希斯顿打给妻子的电话
That phone call to Hixton's wife
是从列克星敦500街区打出的
came from the 500 block of Lexington.
我估计拿不到更精准的地址了
I don't think we can get a more exact address,
-我们只能挨家排查了  -也许不用
- So we're gonna have to canvass. - Well, maybe not.
我刚刚在他的财务里看到了列克星敦大街
I-I just saw Lexington avenue in his financials.
没错  在这
Yeah. Right here.
他上个月开了两张支票  每张都是1万美元
He wrote 2 checks last month, $10,000 each,
开给一个叫做米奇实业的公司
to a company called Meech Industries.
米奇  洛根·米奇吗
Meech? Logan meech?
是啊  他是业主
Yeah, he's listed here as the owner.
-你认识他  -是啊  我逮捕他的次数
- You know him? - Yeah, I must have arrested the guy,
大概有六七次  他是一个低劣的诈骗者
like, half a dozen times. He's a low-rent scam artist
有暴力史
with a history of violence.
上次我逮捕他的时候   他想把一个家伙
Last time I busted him, he was trying to grill cheese
-挤进干洗机  做成烤奶酪   -希斯顿为什么
- a guy in a dry cleaning press. - Why would Hixton
会给这种人开支票呢
be writing checks to a character like that?
洛根·米奇
Logan Meech.
探长
Detective.
我很喜欢你的新...
I love what you've done with your--
坐下
Sit down.
新人是谁
Who's the new guy?
怎么  等待执行死刑的时候
Why, you want to send him
想给他寄圣诞卡吗
Christmas cards from death row?
什么  等等  我没杀人
What? Wait. I didn't kill anybody.
那么杰·希斯顿被杀不久前
So it's just a coincidence that you were with Jay Hixton
你和他在一起是巧合咯
shortly before he was shot to death in his apartment?
什么  希斯顿死了
What? Hixton's dead?
他是我的投资人
Uh, he was one of my investors.
是吗
Really?
希斯顿投资什么了
What is it Mr. Hixton was investing in?
我的救援组织
My relief organization.
为什么我觉得
Why is it I'm thinking,
希斯顿先生提供的唯一救援
the only relief Mr. Hixton's money provided
都跑到了你的账户里呢
was to your own bank account?
希斯顿是发现你诈骗他了吗
Did Hixton get on to your scamming him?
他是不是威胁要报警
Did he threaten to go to the cops?
-你是不是因此杀了他  -我说了
- Is that why you killed him? - I told you,
我没杀他
I didn't kill him.
-我好几周没见他了  -真有趣
- I-I hadn't seen him in weeks. - That's funny,
因为我跟你房东谈过  他说
because I talked to your landlord, and he said that
他记得很清楚
he remembers clearly seeing
希斯顿昨晚去了你家
Hixton at your place last night.
我看你要么是实话实说  老实交代
So either you start telling us the truth and playing ball,
要么我给地方检察官打电话
or I call the DA and
让他们起草谋杀指控
get them to draw up murder charges.
好吧  等等
Okay, look, hang on a minute now.
也许我说错了
Um, maybe, I, uh, I misspoke, okay?
呃
Um...
希斯顿昨晚的确来找过我
Hixton did actually pay me a visit last night.
为什么
Why?
他想要把枪
He wanted a gun.
-干什么用  -防身  他害怕
- For what? - Uh, protection. He wa scared.
他花1000美元买了把点357
He paid me a grand for a-a .357
那把枪我是给朋友留着的
that I was holding for a friend.
他怕什么
What was he scared of?
他的过去
His past.
他说他的过去要反咬他一口
He said it was coming back to get him.
什么意思  他的过去
What's that mean, his past was
要反咬他一口
coming back to get him?
为什么找米奇买枪
And why go to Meech for a gun?
为什么不报警  或是雇保镖
Why not just go to the police or hire a bodyguard?
也许他认为他们保护不了他
Maybe he didn't think they could protect him.
鉴证组检查了希斯顿的公寓
CSU finished processing Hixton's apartment,
发现了两组
came across two sets of
和系统中匹配的指纹
fingerprints that were in the system.
两个来自希斯顿家乡
Couple of career criminals from
弗罗里达的惯犯
Hixton's hometown in Florida.
格雷格和泰·佩奇
Greg and Ty Page.
曾经因抢银行被逮捕
Previous busts for bank robbery
现在因盗窃案服刑5年
and currently serving a nickel for grand larceny.
那个消息有点滞后
Yeah, well, that info's a little bit behind.
他们因为监狱过于拥挤上周得以释放
They were released last week due to overcrowding.
说说他们抢的是谁
Yeah, get to the part about who they robbed.
-希斯顿  -在他中奖一个月后
- Hixton. - A month after he collected his jackpot.
尽管他们带着滑雪面具
Even though they wore ski masks,
他还是认出了他们的声音
he recognized them by their voices
因为他们从小一起长大
because they grew up together.
是他的证词使得他们锒铛入狱
It was his testimony that put them away.
希斯顿一定是听说他们被释放了
Hixton must have heard they were being released
担心他们会来找他报复
and worried they were coming after him again.
根据弗罗里达警方的说法
According to Florida police,
兄弟二人在家待了两天
the brothers were in town for all of two days
就收拾行李  开车北上
before the packed up their car and headed up north.
告诉邻居他们要去捕猎
Told a neighbor that they were going hunting.
看来他们捕到了一个彩票中奖者
Looks like they bagged themselves a lottery winner.
天啊
Whoa!
看来今天你的惊喜遗产
Looks like you made a serious dent
被你挥霍了不少
in your surprise inheritance.
是不是可以说全纽约的动物花纹
Is it safe to say there is not an animal print left
-都被买光了呢  -真好笑
- in any store in New York City? - Very funny.
估计是这样
Probably true.
恭喜你
Well, congratulations.
看起来你成功地完成了中头彩
Looks like you have successfully completed the first stage
五部曲中的第一步  购物
in the five stages of hitting the jackpot--shopping.
下一步是什么
What's the next stage?
如果你是我那位中彩票的被害人
Well, if you were my lottery-winning victim,
你会转做慈善
you'd turn to charity,
然后在你的起居室被射杀
and then get shot to death in your living room.
算了
I'll pass.
再说  我打算把钱还回去
Besides, I've decided to give back the money.
什么  为什么
What? Why?
理查德  我本来要和他分手的
Richard, I was about to break up with the man.
你认为如果他知道的话
Do you really think he would've left me that money
还会给我留遗产吗
if he'd know that?
不不  我要把东西还回去
No, no. I'm gonna return all this stuff.
把钱也还回去  这样做才是对的
I'm gonna give back the money. It's the right thing to do.
你一下跳到第五步了
Well, you've just jumped to stage five.
释怀
Enlightenment.
不过  切特真是喜欢我
Then again, Chet did adore me,
所以我想我可以留下一件
so I think I should be able to keep one thing.
不是真的皮草
It's not real.
贝克特探长
Ah, Detective Beckett.
打电话来是要给我讲睡前故事吗
Did you call to tell me a bedtime story?
哪辆车是他们的
Which car is theirs?
那面红色那辆  弗罗里达牌照
The maroon one over there. Florida plates.
注册在格雷格·佩奇名下
It's registered to a Greg Page.
我们对他的牌照发了警报
We put an alert on their plate number,
一小时前  交警给他们开罚单时
which got triggered when a traffic cop ticketed them
警报触发
about an hour ago.
知道他们在哪吗
Any idea where they are?
不知道
None.
我们就监视着  直到有人出现
So we watch the car until someone shows up.
有什么情况吗
Any sign yet?
没有异样
That's a negative.
酿酒厂  是吗
A winery, huh?
珍妮和我第一次度假的时候参观过一个
Jenny and I visited one on our first vacation together.
一亿美元  你想变成一个农民
$100 mil, and you're gonna become a farmer?
那个未婚妻真是对你造成了严重伤害啊  兄弟
The fiancee really has done some damage on you, bro.
-说得好像蕾妮没有改变你似的  -蕾妮
- Like Lanie hasn't changed you? - Lanie?
拜托  老兄  我们都知道你们两个的地下情了
Come on, dude. We--we all know about the two of you.
卡塞尔和贝克特也知道了吗
Castle and Beckett know, too?
你之前说钱不会改变我们
You said earlier that money doesn't change us,
只会放大我们的个性
it just magnifies who we are.
你赚了大钱  你的什么个性被放大了
W-what did your windfall magnify in you?
一开始...是我那未泯的童心
My inner child... At first.
有点像希斯顿
Kind of like Hixton.
变成那种喜欢
The one who likes, you know,
私人喷气机啊  各种五星酒店什么的
private jets, five-star everything.
但我随后发现
But then I realized,
我真正在乎的奢侈品其实是自由
the only luxury I truly care about is freedom.
写作的自由
You know, freedom to write,
自由支配和阿丽克西斯在一起的时间
to spend time with Alexis.
有了那些钱
Having that money just...
使得我可以过我想要的生活
allows me to live life on my terms.
-你长大了  -我可不会那样说
- You grew up. - Well, I wouldn't go that far.
月球那份地产
That property on the moon?
我上个月才买的
I just bought that last month.
那个人是谁
And who is this guy?
看  辫子头  十二点钟方向
Yo, dreadlocks, 12:00.
纽约警察  让我看到你的手
NYPD, let me see your hands.
-佩奇兄弟  他们在哪  -楼上
- Page brothers, where are they? - Upstairs.
*快滚开  快滚开*
*Move that ass, move that ass*
*趴地上  趴地上*
*Get on the floor, get on the floor*
*我进门时  热辣如火*
*Sexy as hell as I come through the door*
*12把猎枪  趴地上*
*12-gauge shotgun, get on the floor*
*跳上柜台  把钱拿出来*
*Jump on the counter, let off a round*
*趴地上的时候你也尿了裤子*
*You wet yourself as you hit the ground*
*注意点  别出声*
*Take command with my outside voice*
*这地方我们抢定了  你没有机会*
*We're robbin' this bitch, you ain't got no choice*
*别按警报  别哭喊要妈妈*
*Don't hit the alarm, don't beg for your mama*
*把钱放袋里  不然崩了你*
*fill up that bag, won't be no drama won't be no drama*
关掉它
Shut it down.
*趴地上  趴地上*
*get on the floor, get on the floor*
搞什么飞机
What the hell, yo?
录得正顺呢
That was slammin'.
三个武装警察加上一个作家
Three armed cops and a writer makes four,
你们被逮捕了  该你们趴地上了
you're under arrest, so get on the floor.
这里大概有六万
Got about 60 grand here.
你谋杀希斯顿的时候
Where's the other $40,000
从保险箱拿走的剩下的四万在哪
you took from Hixton's safe when you killed him?
是不是都花在你的饶舌事业上了
You spend it on your rap career?
不  你误会了  小个子
Nah, you got it all wrong, shorty.
我们没有杀他
We didn't kill the man.
我们是来这里帮他的
We came up here to help him.
我们脱离帮派  现在是良民
Got out the joint for good behavior.
兄弟打给我们  说他需要救星
Dude called us up, said he needed a savior.
别再饶舌了  我会买你们唱片的
Stop rapping. I'll buy the album.
救星
Savior?
没错  他女儿又开始吸毒了
Yeah. His daughter got back into the drugs.
他要采取些措施  所以找我们了
He needed to make things right, so he called us.
你们俩在佛罗里达州持枪抢劫希斯顿
The two of you robbed Hixton at gunpoint in Florida.
-他怎么会找你们  -希斯顿意识到
- Why would he call you? - When Hixton realized
尼可卷入了什么样的麻烦
what kind of trouble Nicole was in,
他知道我们是唯一能指望的人
He knew we were the only people he could turn to.
那你们到底能做什么去帮他的女儿
And what could you possibly do to help his daughter
戒掉毒瘾
with her addiction?
问题不是毒品  而是她的毒品供应商
Problem wasn't the drugs. It was her dealer.
一个叫奥兹的家伙
A cat named Oz.
尼可被他操控迷惑了
Nicole was under his spell somethin' fierce.
当希斯顿知道后  他去找了奥兹
And when Hixton found out about it, he went to go see Oz,
告诉他"离我女儿远一点"
told the man, "Stay away from my daughter."
但奥兹不肯  他就找了我们
When Oz didn't, he called us.
你不相信我的话  看我的钱包里面
You don't believe me, look in my wallet.
看来尼可撒谎了
Looks like Nicole lied to me
她说她不认得他
when she told me she didn't recognize him.
这就是希斯顿在监视的那个人
It's the guy Hixton had under surveillance.
这是奥兹吗
Is this Oz?
是的  当希斯顿打给我们
Yep. When Hixton called us,
我们立马开车过来
we drove right up here.
我们把奥兹从市中心的俱乐部里拽了出来
Jumped Oz outside this club downtown.
泰用管子修理了他的保镖
Yo, Ty hit his bodyguard with a pipe.
我将奥兹塞进后车箱  开到桥下
I stuffed Oz in the trunk, drove under the bridge,
揍了他一顿
and beat on his ass.
然后我们回到这里
Then we came straight here,
一直唱到现在
been bouncin' tunes ever since.
真的吗  他们昨晚过来了吗
Is that true? Did they come here last night?
没错  我们跟那家伙说
Yeah, we told the man,
"最好离尼可远点
"Best stay away from Nicole
否则我们就把你丢进河里"
Or we gon' put your ass in the river."
他说我们应该这样做  否则的话
He told us we should do it, cause if we let him live,
他会把我们活活烧死
he was gonna burn us alive.
你想知道谁杀了希斯顿  肯定是奥兹了
You wanna know who killed Hixton? Gotta be Oz.
那么希斯顿弄了把枪用来防范奥兹
So Hixton gets a gun to protect himself from Oz.
他不能找警察庇护
He can't go to the cops
因为那会令他女儿有麻烦
'cause that'll get his daughter in trouble.
-发生什么事了   -莱恩  看住他们
- What the hell was that? - Ryan, watch them.
呆着别动
Stay right where you are.
看来奥兹说要活活烧死他们
Well, looks like Oz wasn't kidding
并不是在开玩笑
when he said he'd burn 'em alive.
真的吗  尼可  你又开始吸毒了
Is it true, Nicole? Did you start using again?
我戒毒后  奥兹来找我
After I got clean, Oz found me.
他说他希望我回去
He said he wanted me back.
- 尼可  -抱歉  妈妈
- Nicole. -I'm sorry, mom.
我很抱歉
I'm so sorry.
-你爸知道吗  -他责怪自己
- And your father knew? - He blamed himself.
他说他会搞定的
He said that he was gonna fix it all,
但我没想过
but I never thought...
这叫奥兹的家伙
This Oz--
你认为他有能力杀害你父亲吗
you think he's capable of killing your dad?
全都是我的错  爸爸是因我而死的
This is all my fault. Dad is dead because of me.
没事的
It's okay.
奥兹  又名马文·奥斯门科沃斯基
Oz-- A.K.A. Marvin Osminkowski.
难怪他要改名
No wonder he changed his name.
罪案科的资料显示  他有一个赚钱的小窍门
According to vice, he has a lucrative gig
就是贩卖高端毒品给城里的富人及明星
peddling high-end product to the city's rich and famous,
而汽车炸弹绝对是他的作案手法
and a car bomb is definitely his M.O.
去年他以同样手法炸死了个竞争者
A competing dealer got blown up last year,
但鉴于缺乏证据无法定罪
but they didn't have enough evidence to convict.
那么奥兹因为被打  射杀了希斯顿
So Oz shoots Hixton for ordering the beatdown,
然后企图炸死佩奇兄弟
and then attempts to barbecue the Page brothers
进行报复
to complete his revenge.
好的  去逮捕奥兹吧
All right. Let's go pick up Oz.
那个有点难度
Yeah, well, that's gonna be difficult.
罪案科的资料显示  奥兹几乎在地下活动
According to vice, Oz pretty much operates off grid.
只有在夜总会进行交易时
The only time he's on is when he's dealing
才会出现  而且他在那里
out of word-of-mouth nightclubs, and even there, he's got
有一大群保镖  侍应跟老主顾也会把风
a network of bouncers, waiters, and patrons as lookouts.
奥兹一有风吹草动
Oz catches one whiff of bacon,
就消失得无影无踪
and he vanishes into thin air.
肯定有办法能偷偷溜进去的
There's gotta be some way to slip under the radar.
干嘛
What?
我想我们要用到你的法拉利了
I think we're gonna need your Ferrari.
老妈
Mother.
噢  看看你  你看起来太美了
Oh, my. Look at you. Oh, you look gorgeous.
我只是来拿钥匙顺便换身衣服
I'm just gonna grab my keys and change.
你俩终于要去约会了吗
You two going out on a date?
噢  不
Oh, no.
我们只是去做些便衣工作
We're just doing a little undercover work.
你最近怎么样
So how are you doing?
原来是还不错
I've been better.
卡塞尔告诉我你决定要把钱还给他们
Castle told me that you decided to give the money back.
没错  我试过了  但切特的孩子拒绝了
Yeah, well, I tried. Chet's kids refused to take it.
他们说  他们的父亲很爱我
They said, their father loved me,
他希望我拿着这些钱
He wanted me to have the money.
所以我
So I'm...
在想到底该拿这些钱怎么办
You know, trying to figure out what to do with it.
我目前的想法似乎都很
Everything I come up with seems so...
自私和短浅
Selfish and petty.
噢  不要这样想
Oh, well, it doesn't have to be that way.
你知道么  有人告诉过我
You know, someone once told me that
金钱不会改变你
money doesn't change you,
只会放大你的个性
it just magnifies who you are.
你在乎过切特
You cared about Chet.
或许你能用这些钱来
maybe you could do something
做些对他表示敬意的事
that would honor his memory somehow.
这主意太好了
That is a lovely thought.
谢谢  真的谢谢你
Thank you. Really, thank you.
好了  拿了钥匙
All right. Got the keys.
噢  很好  我来开车
Oh, great. I'm driving.
你来开
You're driving?
贝克特  这是  这是法拉利
Beckett, this is-- this is a ferrari.
是辆高性能的车
It is a high-performance vehicle,
它的设计理念就是需要瞬间反应
designed to respond instantaneously
你的每个念头  每个动作  每个
to your every whim, your every movement, every--
车子不错
Nice car.
去拿些饮料
Get us some drinks
还有紧盯着奥兹  好吗
and keep your eyes peeled for Oz, okay?
好的
Okay.
饮料  没问题
Drinks. Got it.
伙计  拜托了  我一定要过去见他
Ah, come on. Please. You gotta let me go in and see him.
嘿
Hey.
你也嘿  我之前没在这看过你
Hey yourself. I haven't seen you around here before.
噢  那是因为我刚搬来
Oh, that's because I just came into town.
-噢  是吗  -没错
- Oh, yeah? - Yeah.
-从哪来的  -伊比沙岛
- From where? - Ibiza.
有人告诉我  你可是个传说哦
Mm. So a little birdie told me all about you.
-是吗  -对  说你晓得怎样令派对
- Yeah? -Yeah. Said that you know how to keep
嗨一整晚
a party going all night long.
那人有名字吗
Little birdie got a name?
当然
Of course.
-你要告诉我吗  -不
- Are you gonna tell me what it is? - No.
好的  我来了
Yeah, I'm coming.
那是你的男朋友吗
That your boyfriend?
现在不是了
For now.
我喜欢你
I like you.
-是吗  -没错
- Yeah? - Yeah.
证明一下
Well, prove it.
你想要参加什么样的派对
What kind of party you lookin' to get into?
我喜欢闪亮的感觉
Um... I like to feel shiny.
-闪亮啊  -对
- Shiny, huh? - Yeah.
我想我有合适的
I think I got something to fit that bill.
但价钱可不便宜
But it's gonna cost you.
没事  好东西总是贵的
That's okay. Good things always do.
啊
Aah!
嘿
Hey!
噢
ooh.
你傻啊  我要手铐
No. Handcuffs.
哦对
Right.
你在服装的品位退了一大步
You sure took a big step down in the wardrobe department.
你将要退更大一步
You're about to take and even bigger step down--
穿上监狱囚衣
Into a prison jumpsuit.
我们在你企图贩毒的
We got you dead to rights
时候当场将你逮捕
On possession with the intent to sell.
要判二十年牢狱
That's 20 years federal time.
但那跟一级谋杀罪名的
But that's nothing compared to
服刑时间相比算不了什么
the time that you're gonna do for first-degree murder.
更别说引起爆炸的重罪了
Not to mention felony blowing crap up.
我不晓得你在说什么
I don't know what you're talking about.
你认得这家伙吗
You remember this guy?
你应该要认得  你杀了他
You should. You killed him.
还试着用汽车炸弹杀了这两个人
And these two you tried to kill with a car bomb.
我必须给那俩乡巴佬点颜色瞧瞧
Look... I had to get those country boys back.
但我没对希斯顿做任何事  我发誓
But I didn't have anything to do with Hixton. I swear.
目前情况是这样的  马文
Here's a thing, Marvin--
我们给希斯顿住址附近的人看你的照片
We showed your picture around Hixton's place.
说也奇怪  有人看到你在
Oddly enough, people saw you there
案发时间出现在那里
right about the time he was killed.
佩奇兄弟狠狠揍了你一顿
Page brothers gave you a serious beating,
你发誓要报仇  然后希斯顿就死了
you vowed revenge, and then Hixton shows up dead
而且有目击者在犯案现场看到你
with witnesses claiming to see you at the crime scene?
这对你并不乐观  马文
That doesn't look good for you, Marvin,
对我们撒谎只会令情况更糟
and lying to us will only make it worse.
好吧
Okay.
或许  我对自己的身体状况不满
Maybe... I had hard feelings about my medical condition,
或许我打算去找希斯顿谈谈
and maybe I paid Hixton a visit to discuss them.
但我还没进门就放弃找他了
But I abandoned ship before I got to his door.
你急着要当面跟希斯顿说清楚
You were hot to straighten Hixton out,
然后又改变了主意吗
And you changed your mind?
你真的认为我会相信你吗
Do you really expect us to believe that?
这是事实
It's the truth.
我坐电梯到上希斯顿的住处
I took the elevator up to Hixton's place,
电梯门打开后
When the doors opened,
有个家伙站在那儿
there was a guy standing right there.
他看见我了
He got a good look at me.
要是我还去找他的话
If I would've gone though with my visit,
那人肯定很容易就能指证我
he woulda pointed me out in a lineup, easy.
所以我走了
So I walked away.
你看清楚这家伙了吗
You get a good look at this guy?
是的  我们一起坐电梯到一层
Yeah. Rode back down to the first floor with him.
他大概五十岁
He was maybe 50,
绅士打扮  穿着一件经典燕尾服
proper looking, wearing an old-school tuxedo.
真的是管家干的
The butler really did do it.
管家伊斯利
Easley the butler--
忠诚  尽责
Loyal, devoted,
表面上因为主人的死极度伤心
seemingly distraught over the death of his master.
但始终隐藏在这顺从卑屈
Yet all the while, lurking behind that mask
的面具后面的  是一个杀手
of servile correctness... was a killer.
或者奥兹只是想扰乱我们的视线
Or Oz is just trying to kick up some dust.
我是说  管家的动机是什么
I mean, what's the butler's motive?
在小说里  通常都是两个原因
Well, in fiction, it would be one of two things.
第一个  他跟主人的妻子
Firstly, he was carrying on a torrid affair
-在暗度陈仓  -恶
- with his master's wife. - Ew.
另一个  就是跟钱有关
Second, had to be the money.
我想卡塞尔或许猜对了
I think Castle might be on to something.
我深入调查了雷金纳德·伊斯利
I dug a little deeper into Reginald Easley,
他过去几任雇主都说
and his last few employers all say the same thing--
伊斯利都在某些昂贵物品失踪后辞职
Easley resigned after some of their valuables went missing.
我意识到  我一直都想错方向了
I realized, I've been thinking about this all wrong.
你不是一个轻佻的人
You're not a frivolous person,
所以你不会用中彩票的钱
so you wouldn't do frivolous things
-做轻佻的事  -卡塞尔
- with your lottery winnings. - Castle.
不  我会查个水落石出的  如果你
No, no. I'm gonna figure this out. If you...
在收拾包袱吗
Packing your things?
这些不是我的
These aren't my things.
全都属于我的雇主
They belong to my employer.
肯定很辛苦  被这样一堆财产围绕着
Must be hard, being around all this wealth,
但全都不是你的
none of it yours.
-我对自己的待遇很满意  -真的吗
- I'm content with my lot. - Really?
我们查了你的背景
We read up on you.
在利兹的一个单亲家庭出身
Born in Leeds to a single mother
母亲是一个裁缝
who was a seamstress.
经过训练后  你改掉了你的口音
With the right training, you lost the lowbrow accent
学习如何跻身名流社会
and learned to fit in with the gentry,
你见到这些人一天就能花光
where you saw people spend more in one day
你母亲工作一年的钱
than your mother made in an entire year.
然后你遇到了希斯顿
Then along comes Hixton,
一个身世背景跟你相似的人
a man with an upbringing not unlike your own.
但这些都是属于他的  你也是他的
But he owned all this, and he owned you,
并不是因为任何特长或才智
and not because of any special talent or intelligence.
只是因为他猜到了六个数字
Just because he guessed six numbers,
而你没有
and you didn't.
从希斯顿那儿拿到的并不算是偷
And taking from Hixton wasn't really stealing.
只是为了更正命运的不公
It was just correcting a karmic injustice.
你逼他打开保险箱
You made him open that safe,
但你不知道他有枪
but what you didn't know was that he had a gun,
但他伸手去拿枪时  事情最终发展成这样
and when he reached for it, this is where it ended.
你怎么会这样想
What on earth makes you think that?
我们知道他被杀害当晚
We know that you were here
你在这里  伊斯利先生
the night that he was killed, Mr. Easley,
比你说你离开的时间更晚
long after you said that you had left.
不久前  他买了二十五本狄更斯的初版书
Early on, he bought 25 first edition Dickens...
查尔斯·狄更斯  他连看都没看过
Charles Dickens-- and the man didn't even read.
他只是喜欢书脊上
He just liked the look of the leather
-的皮革  -伊斯利先生
- on their spines. - Mr. Easley--
我偷了其中的两本
I stole two of them.
对我来说  就权当他作为
To me, it was like levying a tax
一个白痴给国家上税了
on him for being an idiot.
但后来我改变了主意
But then I had a change of heart.
我晚上把它们带回来了  十一点左右的时候
I brought them back here that night, around 11:00,
以为他和他妻子出去了
thinking he was out with his wife.
但因为某些原因他却在这儿
But for some reason he was here.
我听见淋浴的声音
I...I heard the shower running.
他被杀的那天夜里
Your excuse for coming back here
你返回这儿的理由
the night that he was killed
就是你改变了主意吗
was that you had a change of heart?
是的
Yes.
我倒愿意说是因为他转向慈善事业的行为
I'd like to say it was because his turn to philanthropy
让我对他刮目相看
made me see him in a different light,
作为一个好人他不应该被别人偷东西
as a good man one shouldn't steal from.
但实际上是因为  我吓坏了
But the truth is, I was scared
他的霉运可能会转到我身上
his bad luck would become mine.
他中了一亿美元的彩票
He won over $100 million in the lottery.
这算是哪门子的霉运啊
One could hardly consider that bad luck.
他婚姻失败  女儿染上了毒品
Mm. His marriage failed, his daughter fell into drugs,
而且他刚刚在自己公寓被枪杀
and he was just gunned down in his own apartment.
这就是天地万物的规律
That, sir, is the universe...
你刚才管这叫什么来着
what did you call it?
哦对了  "更正命运的不公"
Oh, yes, "Correcting a karmic injustice."
你这是什么意思
What do you mean?
中奖的那张彩票
The winning lottery ticket.
在喝了不少酒之后
Hixton let it slip one night
希斯顿有天晚上说漏了嘴
after a little too much time with the bottle.
他总是下注相同的数字
He always played the same numbers...
他和他妻子相遇和结婚的日子
the dates he and his wife met and were married
010395和102498
010395 and 102498.
彩票上并没有这些数字
None of those numbers are on the ticket.
所有的痛苦都来源于金钱吗
All the misery that came from the money?
希斯顿这么认为是因为他偷了彩票
Hixton believed it was because he stole the ticket.
你们觉得希斯顿是因为
So you think hixton was murdered
偷了彩票而被谋杀吗
because he stole the ticket?
-不  -是
- No. - Yes.
得了吧  你...我的意思是
Come on. You...I mean,
这彩票价值一大笔钱呢
it was worth a fortune.
伊斯利完全有理由编造一个那样的故事
Easley had every reason to make up that story,
即使那些不是希斯顿的常规数字
and even if those weren't hixton's regular numbers,
这也不能证明是他偷了彩票
it still doesn't prove that he stole the ticket.
但偷彩票解释通了很多希斯顿的行为
But the theft explains so much about Hixton's behavior.
救济所的主管
The director of the soup kitchen
说希斯顿强迫症一样地发钱
said that Hixton compulsively gave away his money,
就像他根本不值得拥有它们一样
like he felt he didn't deserve it.
我管这叫中奖者的愧疚
I called it winner's guilt.
但如果这完全是另外一种愧疚呢
But what if it was another kind of guilt entirely?
那好吧  我们就暂定你是对的
Okay, fine. Let's say that you're right.
我们假设是希斯顿偷了彩票
Let's say that Hixton stole the ticket.
但依然没有证据证明
There's still no evidence suggesting the
这导致了他的死
that contributed to his death.
你是第一个告诉我
You're the first person to tell me
在谋杀案调查中没有巧合可言的人
that there are no coincidences in a murder investigation.
等下  警官
Hold on, detective.
他说中了  你说希斯顿告诉米奇
He's got a point. You said Hixton told Meech
他的过去又找上门来了
his past was coming back to get him.
我们以为是佩奇兄弟
Now we thought he meant the Page brothers.
但这张彩票揭示了
But this ticket represents
发生在他身上最大的一件事
the biggest thing that ever happened to him.
我管这叫谋杀的主要动机
I call that a major motive for murder.
好吧  如果这是真的我们该怎样证明
Okay, fine. Then if it's true, how do we prove it?
通过数字啊
The numbers.
2  4  8
2, 4, 8...
19  41  和79
19, 41, and 79.
我知道这希望渺茫
I know it's a long shot,
但如果我们研究出这些数字的含义
but if we can figure out what these numbers signify,
我们有可能找到彩票真正的主人
we might be able to find the ticket's real owner.
我用我孩子的生日下注
I play my kids' birthdays.
我用第一次上床和格斗的日期下注
I play my firsts-- sex and combat.
我跟他一样
I play his firsts, too.
咋了  这样的话我们俩都能赢
What? That way, we both win,
而且一点也不尴尬
and it's not awkward.
-贝克特你呢  -对不起我不下注  卡塞尔
- Beckett? - Uh, sorry. I don't play, Castle.
-但如果你下注呢  -这无关紧要  卡塞尔
- But if you did? - Well, it doesn't really matter, Castle.
事实上是
I mean, the fact is,
希斯顿一年前中了彩票
Hixton won the lottery a year ago.
如果他是偷的那张彩票
If he stole that ticket,
真正的中奖者为什么不站出来呢
why didn't the rightful owner come forward sooner?
也许真正的中奖者死了
Maybe the rightful owner is dead.
也许是希斯顿杀了他
Maybe Hixton killed him.
月球上的地  希斯顿所做的奇怪的购买
The moon. The weird purchases hixton made.
他刚一赢钱  就买了月球上三英亩的地
As soon as he won, he bought 3 acres on the moon
还为他邻居买了一座陵墓
and a mausoleum for his neighbor.
-查出所有关于他邻居的事  -这就去
- Find out everything we can on this neighbor.- I'm on it.
如果你是对的  卡塞尔  我打赌希斯顿的邻居
If you're right, Castle, I'm betting Hixton's neighbor
没料到他这辈子最幸运的日子
never imagined that the luckiest day of his life
-也是他的祭日  -我赞成
- would also be his last.- Boo-yah!
邻居名字叫汉克·沃特斯
Neighbor's name was Hank Walters.
他死于公布彩票中奖结果那天
He died the day the winning numbers were announced.
沃特斯的生日是1941年8月2日
Walters' birthday-- 2/8/41--
彩票上的三个数字
Three of the numbers in the lottery ticket.
两天之后
Two days later,
希斯顿站出来索要他的1.17亿支票
Hixton came forward to claim his $117 million check.
沃特斯死于什么
What did Walters die of?
-自然死亡  -真的吗
- Natural causes.- For real?
没错  他是一个死于
Yeah. He was an old man dying of,
大约六种不同疾病的老人
like, six different things.
蕾妮已经尸检过
Lanie went over the autopsy,
她说所有东西看上去
said everything looked like
都毫无疑点
it was on the up-and-up.
也就是说沃特斯早已卧床不起
So Walters is bedridden.
希斯顿就像是所有好邻居一样  问老人
Hixton, like any good neighbor, asks the old man
有什么他能为他做的
if there's anything he can do for him.
沃特斯说  帮我买张彩票
Walters says, "Yes, buy me a lottery ticket."
也许这只是一锤子买卖
Maybe it was a onetime thing.
也许他一直这样做
Maybe he did it all the time.
这次  中奖数字公布后
This time, the numbers are announced,
沃特斯中奖了
and Walters won.
希斯顿冲回去告诉他  却发现沃特斯死了
Hixton rushes back to tell him and finds Walters dead.
他不知该怎么办
And doesn't know what to do.
这就是为什么他隔了两天才站出来
That's why it took him an extra day to come forward.
他在做思想道德上的斗争
He was struggling with the moral implications.
没错  但人有多大胆  地有多大产
Yeah, but desperate times call for desperate measures.
他声称彩票是他自己的
He claimed the ticket as his own.
很显然没别人知道此事
Clearly no one else knew about it.
那家人呢  沃特斯有家人吗
What about family? Did walters have any?
根据记录  汉克·沃特斯唯一活着的亲属
According to county records, the only living relative
是一个叫汤姆的侄子
of Hank Walters is a nephew named Tom,
-猜猜他住在哪  -纽约
- and guess where he lives.- New york city.
抱歉
I'm sorry.
你是在说我继承了一亿美元吗
Are you telling me that I might inherit $100 million?
得了吧  汤姆  你早都知道了
Come on, tom. You already figured that out.
你与希斯顿对峙
You confronted Hixton.
你告诉他你想要回财产
You told him you wanted restitution.
他说不行  然后事情就恶化了
He said no. Things got ugly.
最终希斯顿死了
And hixton ended up dead.
你把保险箱里的东西据为己有
So you grabbed what was in the safe
然后逃之夭夭
and you took off.
-什么  -别装了  Tom
- What? - Knock it off, Tom.
你是老人的唯一亲属
You're the old man's only living relative.
你是唯一有复仇动机的人
You're the only one with motive for revenge.
不  我不是他唯一的亲属  他有个儿子
No, I'm not his only relative. He's got a son.
不  他没有  我们查过了
No, he doesn't. We checked.
当然  不是他亲生的
Well, sure. He's not biological.
汉克和他妈妈约会了大概五年
Hank dated his mom for, like, five years
当这孩子渐渐长大
While the kid was growing up.
他们两人情同父子
The two bonded like crazy.
在分手后他俩仍然保持联系
Kept in touch even after the romance broke up.
甚至在过去的十年里
They even spent every holiday together
他们每个假期都一起过
for the last ten years.
这个儿子  他的生日是1979年4月19日吗
This son, is his birthday 4/19/79?
是啊  你怎么知道的
Uh, yeah. How'd you know?
因为这是中奖彩票上
Because those are the three remaining numbers
剩下的三个数字
in the winning lottery ticket.
你没告诉我们你到底是谁  你撒谎了肖恩
You lied to us about who you are, Shawn.
这是你爸爸的中奖号码
These are your dad's numbers...
他的生日和你的生日
Your birthday and his.
我不知道你在说什么
I don't know what you're talking about.
你什么时候意识到希斯顿
When did you realize that Hixton had stolen
偷了中奖的彩票
the winning ticket?
是你还在孟菲斯监狱里的时候吗
Was it when you were still in prison in Memphis?
还是你出来以后
Or was it after you got out,
你去看望你爸爸
went to go and visit your dad,
发现他已经去世了
found out he was dead
他的陵墓是由他被盗的
and that his mausoleum was paid
那笔钱支付的
for with his stolen winnings?
我简直无法想像你的感受
I can't imagine how you must have felt,
是什么驱使着你来到纽约
how driven you were to come to New York,
把事情逐一料理好
make things right.
你在救济所追踪到了希斯顿
You tracked down hixton at the soup kitchen,
威胁他如果不按你说的做
threatened him with all kinds of things
你会不择手段
if he didn't do right by you.
他吓坏了  把车给了你
He freaked out. He gave you his car.
但这远远不够  是吗
But that wasn't enough, was it?
你们没有任何证据
You can't prove any of this.
我可以证明这一切  肖恩
I can prove all of it, Shawn.
我们在你的公寓里
We found the money from Hixton's safe
发现了希斯顿保险箱里的钱
in your apartment
上面有大量他的血迹
with trace amounts of his blood in it.
接下来发生了什么
So what happened next?
你为什么带着十万美元就走掉了
I mean, why would you walk away with only 100 grand?
他欠你上百万呢
He owed you millions.
我去他公寓找属于我的东西
I went to his apartment to collect what was mine.
他告诉我...
He told me...
我根本不配拥有这些钱
I didn't deserve the money.
他说我是个人渣罪犯
He said that I was a dirtbag criminal,
如果他把钱给了我  我会做的
And all I was gonna do if he gave it to me
无非就是挥霍一空
was put it up my nose.
取而代之的是  他要把钱全捐出去
Instead, he was gonna give it all away...
给那些需要的人
to those in need.
我告诉他  我就是需要钱的人
I told him, I was in need.
然后他去抓我的枪
Then he grabbed for my gun.
枪走火了
It went off.
那些钱最终怎么处置
So what's gonna happen with all that money?
那是由律师去决定的
Well, that's for the lawyers to decide.
好的一方面是尼可要再次进行戒毒理疗
The good thing is that Nicole is going back into rehab,
等她出来的时候
and her mom's gonna be there for her
她妈妈会在那里等着她
when she gets out.
至少这件事结束后有一些好的结果
Well, at least something good will come of all this.
今天就到这里吧  有些累了  明天见
That is it for me. I am beat. I'll see you tomorrow.
等一下  你放弃了
Wait. You giving up?
不再想问我中大奖以后
No more questions about
内心深处的梦想了吗
my innermost jackpot dreams?
你说你没有梦想啊
You said you didn't have any.
晚安  卡塞尔
Good night, Castle.
晚安
Good night.
晚上好  女士们
Good evening, ladies.
嗨
Hi.
你这是在买房产吗
Are you buying property?
奶奶决定好该如果处置她继承的遗产了
Gram decided what to do with her inheritance.
-我觉得这点子好极了  -真的吗  是什么
- I think it's perfect.- Really, what?
我打算开一家
I'm going to open
玛莎·罗杰斯表演学校
The Martha Rodgers school of acting.
我以为
Oh. I...I thought
你要做一些纪念查特的事
You were gonna do something to honor Chet?
就是在做啊  哦不
Well, I am. Oh, no.
查特一直鼓励我
Chet was always encouraging me
去用我的天赋帮助人们
to use my enormous talent to help people.
难道你不打算取名为
Then wouldn't you call it
切特·帕拉本表演学校吗
The Chet Palaburn school of acting
毕竟是他赞助的
given its auspices?
习惯上来说
Well, it's customary that
当你开了一所学校
when you're opening a school,
你用一位伟大的老师做为它的名字
you use a great teacher's name,
比如斯拉格斯伯格
like, um, Strasberg,
还有梅斯勒艾德乐  现在是罗杰斯
Meisner, Adler, and now Rodgers.
我要去订做一份
Oh, I am, however, going to commission
能挂在学校大厅里的查特的肖像
a portrait to be done of Chet that will hang in the lobby
这样他的遗产就可以永存了
so his legacy will last forever.
不错啊
Nice. Mm.
遗产
Legacy.
怎么了
What? Hmm?
我知道贝克特的梦想了
I know what beckett would do.
*快滚开*
*move that ass*
*快滚开  快滚开*
*move that ass, move that ass*
*趴地上*
*get on the floor*
卡塞尔
Castle.
我知道如果你中了彩票你会怎么做了
I know what you would do if you won the lottery.
当然了  请进吧
By all means, please come in.
关于我永远不会做出的财产决定
So what is your big insight
你有什么大发现了
into a financial decision that I will never have to make?
你会用那些钱
You would use the money
去纪念你妈妈的遗产
to honor your mother's legacy.
在来的路上
On the way over here,
我给你妈妈过去的法学院院长打电话了
I called the dean of your mom's old law school.
我们探讨了关于设立一个
We talked about starting a scholarship
以乔安娜·贝克特名字命名的奖学金
in Johanna Beckett's name.
此奖会给那些打算将其事业奉献给
One that would provide a full ride for a student
在法律系统中没有发言权者的
planning on dedicating their career
同学一条顺利的求学之路
to those in the legal system without a voice.
那些像你妈妈一样的人
The kind of people your mom championed.
而且如你所愿
And with your blessing,
我将以主人身份招待一些捐款者资助此奖
I would like to host a fund-raiser to fund it.
你不插手我的生活会死  对吧
You just can't stay out of my personal life, can you?
谢谢你  这真的很贴心
Thank you. That's really sweet.
我们肯定要邀请市长
We definitely have to invite the mayor
还有所有他竞选的赞助商
and all of his campaign contributors.
他们当中有几个荷包很松  其中有个人叫
Some of 'em can be boorish. They got this one guy...
比利·罗  他很有钱  他有...
Bill Rowe. He's so rich, he has...